KIT - Secuso Research - Results - Privacy Friendly Apps - Privacy Policy

  search

    * Start
    * News

    * Start
    * Events

        * Start
        * Events
        * Research Seminar

        * Start
        * Events
        * Further SECUSO events

        * Start
        * Events
        * Relevant external events

    * Start
    * Staff

        * Start
        * Staff
        * Head of the research group

        * Start
        * Staff
        * Administrative staff

        * Start
        * Staff
        * Postdoctoral researchers

        * Start
        * Staff
        * Research associates

        * Start
        * Staff
        * Student assistants

    * Start
    * Research

        * Start
        * Research
        * Publications

        * Start
        * Research
        * Projects

        * [Decision-Making in Hybrid Adaptive Systems for Better Work and Life - An Open Science Approach](https://secuso.aifb.kit.edu/english/2489.php)

        * Start
        * Research
        * Results

            * Start
            * Research
            * Results
            * Usable S&P Tools

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * Usable S&P Tools
                * Secure Communication

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * Usable S&P Tools
                * User Account Protection

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * Usable S&P Tools
                * Privacy Protection

            * Start
            * Research
            * Results
            * S&P Awarness/Education/Training

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * S&P Awarness/Education/Training
                * Secure Communication

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * S&P Awarness/Education/Training
                * User Account Protection

            * Start
            * Research
            * Results
            * Electronic Voting

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * Electronic Voting
                * Security of Electronic Voting

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * Electronic Voting
                * Special Election Settings

                * Start
                * Research
                * Results
                * Electronic Voting
                * Human Factors

            * Start
            * Research
            * Results
            * Theories and models

    * Start
    * Teaching

        * Start
        * Teaching
        * Courses

        * Start
        * Teaching
        * Theses

* search
    
      search

[Research Group Security • Usability • Society (SECUSO)](https://secuso.aifb.kit.edu/english/index.php "Research Group Security • Usability • Society (SECUSO)")

Privacy Policy
==============

Stand: 22.06.2021

The Privacy Friendly Apps are designed to function with minimized data disclosure, in line with Article 5(1)(c) of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) does not collect any personal data via the Privacy Friendly Apps. Specific functions of certain apps may involve the processing of personal data:

**Weather (Privacy Friendly):**

The app retrieves weather data via the free API of OpenWeatherMap ([https://openweathermap.org/api](https://openweathermap.org/api)). OpenWeatherMap provides information on data protection at [https://openweather.co.uk/privacy-policy](https://openweather.co.uk/privacy-policy).

**Net Monitor (Privacy Friendly):**

For certificate verification (analysis of TLS implementation), a connection is established via the SSL Labs API ([https://www.ssllabs.com/projects/ssllabs-apis/](https://www.ssllabs.com/projects/ssllabs-apis/)). The operator Qualys provides information on data protection at [https://www.qualys.com/company/privacy/](https://www.qualys.com/company/privacy/) including a supplementary EEA Supplement Privacy Policy, which is intended as special information for data sub-jects in the European Economic Area.

**Food-Tracker (Privacy Friendly):**

In order to be able to provide information about products (such as calorie count and name), products are retrieved from the Open Food Facts database ([https://world.openfoodfacts.org/](https://world.openfoodfacts.org/)) at the user's request. However, if the functionality is not desired or needed, the app will work without this permission.

Questions and suggestions regarding the Privacy Friendly Apps can be sent to us via the e-mail address [contact∂secuso.org](mailto:contact@secuso.org). To respond to inquiries, we process your personal data as follows:

**I. Processing of personal data and recipients**

When you contact us by e-mail, the data you provide (usually your e-mail address and name, if applicable) will be stored by us in order to respond to your inquiry. Recipients of the data are the employees of the SECUSO research group at KIT. Employees from the organizational units of the central administration of KIT are only consulted if it is necessary to respond to the inquiry. We delete the personal data collected in this context after the storage is no longer necessary or restrict the processing if there are legal retention obligations.

**II. Controller**

The controller of data processing within the meaning of the GDPR and other data protection legislation:

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT)  
Kaiserstraße 12  
76131 Karlsruhe  
Germany  
Phone.: +49 721 608-0  
Fax: +49 721 608-44290  
E-Mail: [info∂kit.edu](mailto:info@kit.edu)

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) is a corporation governed by public law. It is represented by the President, Prof. Dr.-Ing. Holger Hanselka.

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at [datenschutzbeauftragter∂kit.edu](mailto:datenschutzbeauftragter@kit.edu) or by ordinary mail with “Die Datenschutzbeauftragte” (the data protection officer) being indicated on the envelope.  

**III. Legal basis**

The legal basis for the processing of personal data in connection with your request is Article 6, paragraph 1 (e), paragraph 3 (b) GDPR in conjunction with Section 4 Landesdatenschutzgesetz Baden-Württemberg (LDSG - State data protection act of the state Baden-Württemberg).

**IV. Rights**

You have the following rights regarding your personal data:

* the right to obtain confirmation as to whether data concerning you is being processed and information on the data processed, further information on data processing, and copies of data (Article 15 GDPR)
* the right to rectify or complete inaccurate or incomplete data (Article 16 GDPR)
* the right to erasure of data concerning you without undue delay (Article 17 GDPR)
* the right to restriction of processing (Article 18 GDPR)
* the right to object to the future processing of the data concerning you which is based on Article 6, paragraph 1, point (e) or (f) GDPR (Article 21 GDPR)

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority about the processing of the personal data concerning you by Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) (Article 77 GDPR). Supervisory authority of KIT in the sense of Article 51, paragraph 1 GDPR is according to Article 25, paragraph 1 LDSG:

The State Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information Baden-Württemberg (Landesbeauftragter für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit Baden-Württemberg)

Street address:

Königstraße 10a  
70173 Stuttgart  
Germany

Postal address:

Post office box 10 29 32  
70025 Stuttgart  
Germany

Phone.:  +49 711/615541-0  
Fax: +49 711/615541-15  
E-Mail: [poststelle∂lfdi.bwl.de](mailto:poststelle@lfdi.bwl.de)

### Contact

KIT Campus Süd  
Kollegiengebäude am Kronenplatz ([Bld. 05.20](https://www.kit.edu/campusplan/?id=05.20))  
Kaiserstr. 89  
76133 Karlsruhe

[Newsletter](https://secuso.aifb.kit.edu/english/122.php) subscription  
[YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC67iYdsv5I1DAvlhyPNVgpg) subscription

### Externe Veranstaltungen

**Monday, 08 Jul 2024**  
[9th IEEE European Symposium on Security and Privacy (EuroS&P) 2024](https://secuso.aifb.kit.edu/english/77.php/event/51517#calendar_top)

* * *

**Monday, 15 Jul 2024**  

* * *

**Tuesday, 30 Jul 2024**  
[19th International Conference on Availability, Reliability and Security (ARES) 2024](https://secuso.aifb.kit.edu/english/77.php/event/51522#calendar_top)

* * *

### SECUSO Events

**Wednesday, 02 Oct 2024**  

* * *

**Friday, 08 Nov 2024**  

* * *

last change: 2024-02-26

KIT – The Research University in the Helmholtz Association
